DMITRIY MELNIKOV

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+7 (921) 302 00 52 - melnikovdv@gmail.com - mlayer.org

I'm a software developer. My expertise is in mobile applications development and building great APIs. I like new technology, gadgets and public speaking. Besides IT my passion is swing dancing.

EXPERIENCE

Yandex. Money 2013 – 2014

< 500

https://money.yandex.ru/

Yandex. Money 2011 – 2013

< 500

https://money.yandex.ru/

Sig m a - S of t 2007 - 2011 < 100 persons

< 100 persons http://sigma-soft.ru/

A x o n 2006 – 2007 < 20 persons

EDUCATION

Saint-Petersburg university of waterway communications

2003 - 2008

HEAD OF API DEPARTMENT

I was responsible for the product management of payment system's web services, public API's design and Infrastructure development.

Also I took part in different conferences as a public speaker.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

At the beginning I was part of the backend development team and worked on payment gateways. Later my passion for mobile technology moved me to the mobile development departure. I made an official Yandex. Money Android app.

Priority technologies: Java, Android.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I worked on tools and software for customs needs. E.g. commercial project, which helps to fill customs bills.

Priority technologies: Delphi, Firebird RDBMS, XML.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I helped to develop a set of applications for furniture factory and shops. It included factory software, warehouse and sales part.

Priority technologies: Delphi and Firebird RDBMS.

COMPUTER SCIENCE SPECIALIST

Applied math and computer science.